A Finding Aid to the Hugo Gellert Papers, 1916-1986, in the Archives of American Art AAA.gellhugo
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, circa 1920-1986; Series 2; (Boxes 1-2, 8; 0.8 linear feet)
  Reisman, Philip: 1962, circa 1960s
  Rickey, George: 1937
  Rosen, Max: 1955
  Rosner, A.: 1952, 1959
  Rosner, Deak: 1955
  Rossen, John: 1955
  Rossi, Quintin: 1935
  Royce, Edward: 1955
  Sandburg, Carl: 1942
  Sapiro, Aaron: 1932
  Schappes Defense Committee: 1941 (Morris U. Shappes)
  Schoen, Eugene: 1932, 1934
  Schwartz, Morris: 1951
  Selsam: 1951
  Sequenzia, Sofia: 1983
  Shields, T.A. "Art": 1959
  Shillen, Ronald: 1942
  Siegelbaum, Portia: 1978
  Sillen, Samuel: 1952
  Smith, Jessica: 1952
  Soglow, Otto: 1942
  Solomon: Dave: 1954 (New Talents Gallery), 1956
  Starobin, Joseph: 1955
  Steffens, Lincoln: 1934 (journalist)
  Stone, M. Hedley: 1944
  Street, Julian Jr.: 1940
  Tandy, W. Lou: 1953
  Time: 192-
  Todd, Bianca: 1940 (See also Series 4)
  Tresca, Carlo: circa 1930s (anarchist)
  Turner, Jeannette S.: 1957-1960
  Tyler, Hugh: 1939 (WPA)
  Vallon, Jose: 1934
  Van Rensselaer, Sylvia: 1944 ("Portrait of America Competition" report)
  Weber, Max: 1953 (See also Series 4)
  Weyhe Gallery: 1947
  Wilson, Steve: 1959 (Progressive Lithographers)
  The Worker: 1952 (Rob Hall)
  World Council of Peace: 1955 (Jean Laffitte)
  World: 1925
  Zigrosser, Carl: 1937
  Zorach, Bill: 1942
  Zundel, Eugenia: 1957, 1959
  Zurier, Rebecca: 1984, circa 1980s
  - Correspondence, circa 1920-1929 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1930-1931; (See also Box 8) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, circa 1930-1939 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence, circa 1940-1949 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence, 1950; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 41-42)
  - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence, 1952; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 44-45)
  - Correspondence, 1953; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 46-47)
  - Correspondence, 1954; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 48-49)
  - Correspondence, 1955; (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 50-52)
  - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1957; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1959; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - Correspondence, circa 1950-1959 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1960; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1962, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, circa 1960-1969 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1979 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, circa 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, undated; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
  - Oversized Item from Correspondence (See Box 1, f25) (Box 8 (sol))
- Writings, 1916-1970; Series 3; (Box 2; 0.7 linear feet)
  This series includes essays, short stories, notes, lists, notebooks, and a play. Most writings are by Hugo Gellert. Articles and stories by other authors, particularly Hungarian are also found.
  Gellert's writings include two full-length typescripts, for Baron Munchausen, His Famous 'Mein Kampf', and Comrade Gulliver, An Illustrated Account of Travel into that Strange Country the United States of America. Other prose writings by Gellert include brief essays on a wide array of historical, political, and biographical topics, as well as writings related to exhibitions. Most of these writings are untitled, but examples of titles that are present include "Siqueiros in Jail," "War," The Role of the Communist Artist," and "Charles White, His Portfolio." Prose writings in the Hungarian language are filed separately.
  Proposals and applications consist mainly of biographical information about Gellert and one page of an application for Robert Gwathmey. Notes include lists of names, agendas, supplies, recipes for art media, and expenses. Some of the notes are in Hungarian, and scattered notes in handwriting other than Gellert's are also found. Sketches are common throughout the notes. Notebooks contain contacts, appointments, writings, sketches, and other records.
  Writings by other authors include articles in English and stories in Hungarian by various authors, filed alphabetically by author. These writings are typically typescripts, and include seven stories by the Hungarian realist writer Zsigmond Móricz. The unsigned typescripts filed at the end of the series may or may not be by Hugo Gellert.
  Additional writings are found in the Organizational Records and Artwork series, including an autobiographical essay in a 1950 sketchbook.
  - Writings by Hugo Gellert (Box 2)
    - Baron Munchausen: His Famous Tale ??Mein Kampf,??, circa 1930-1939 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Comrade Gulliver: An Illustrated Account of Travel into that Strange Country, the USA, 1935; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
    - Prose Writings in English, circa 1930-1970; (5 folders) (Box 2, Folder 22-26)
    - Prose Writings in Hungarian, undated; (4 folders; see also Box 8, sol) (Box 2, Folder 27-30)
    - Proposals and Applications, circa 1936-1953 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Lists of Artwork, circa 1930-1960 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Notes, circa 1930-1969; (10 folders; see also Box 8, sol) (Box 2, Folder 33-42)
    - Notebook, circa 1941 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      (Contains sketches)
    - Notebook, circa 1949 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Notebook, circa 1955 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Writings by Others (Box 2)
    - Articles, circa 1962, 1970 and undated; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 46-47)
      (Includes "Jo Davidson" by Van Wyck Brooks, "China Report" by John Chen, an article on the sentence of David Alfaro Siqueiros and Filomeno Mata by Victor Rico Galan, "Second Culture" by Gaylord C. LeRoy, "The Ballad of Gheorghe Doja" by Constantin Palade, and "Facts on New York Labor" by Victor Perlo)
    - Stories in Hungarian, 1916, undated (Box 2, Folder 48-50)
      (authors include Jenö Heltai, Zsigmond Móricz, and István Tömörkény)
  - Unsigned Typescripts (Box 2)
    - Prose Writings in English, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
      (Includes "Chalcography in Hungary," "Political Indifference - Political Death," and untitled essays on the federal art program, artist Robert Minor, and fragments of an essay on the John Reed Club)
    - Prose Writings in Hungarian, undated (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Untitled Three-Act Play in English, circa 1930-1939 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Oversized Writings (See Box 2, f27 and f39) (Box 8 (sol))
- Organizational Records, circa 1920-1977; Series 4; (Boxes 3, 8, and OV 9; 1 linear foot)
  This series contains documents related to political and art organizations for which Gellert was an active organizer, officer, and in some cases, a founder. Because of his central role in many of these organizations, records often contain unique documentation of their activities.
  Typical records found include incoming and outgoing correspondence, membership records, petitions, reports, open letters to public figures in multiple drafts, accounting records, records related to exhibitions, publicity in various forms, meeting agendas and minutes, and Gellert's original notes and writings. Documents are arranged by organization, with records for each organization filed roughly in chronological order. Names of significant correspondents found in this series are listed in a note under the folder heading in which it appears.
  Printed material related to organizations for which no original records are found are filed in the Printed Material series.
  - American Artists Congress, circa 1936-1937, 1942; (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
    (Includes letters of Grace Clements, G. Merangel, Stuart Davis, Thomas Parker, and a 1936 pamphlet of cartoons defending the Works Progress Administration)
  - American Artists Congress, Conference Proceedings, First American Artists Congress against War and Fascism, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Art of Today Gallery, 1954-1958; (10 folders) (Box 3, Folder 5-14)
    (Includes letters of Rockwell Kent, Sally Kent, Hilda Simpson, John Kingsbury, Robert Shinn, Clark Foreman, Emil Zinn, and Eleanor Brown)
  - Art of Today Gallery, Log Books, 1955-1956; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 15-16)
  - Art of Today Gallery, Amalgamated Bank Book and Receipt Book, 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Artists Committee of Action, circa 1934-1935; (6 folders) (Box 3, Folder 18-23)
    (Includes letters of A. Alfred DeVito, Zoltan Hecht, Josephine Droege, Frederick Detwiller, Samuel Henning, Theo. H. Kleffel, Nathaniel Pousette-Dart, Carla Zimmerman, Madeleine Gray, Leo Mansoni, Victor Frisch, Archie Abraham, Constance Clarke, Lionel S. Reiss, Else Mevis, R.A. Griffith, Edith Bryan, S.A. Sliflein, Basil Marros, Lewis Rubin, Rose Hecht, Irving Bulback, Maurice Rawson, Adam A. Sanders, J.J. Lankes, Ralph Pearson, Max Weber, Joseph Lemarzi, Mrs. Henry Breckinridge, Lillian Cohen, Harry Hoffman, Marion Walton, Frannie Engle, R. Pringle, and Olivia Agee)
  - Artists Coordination Committee, circa 1935-1941; (12 folders; see also OV 9) (Box 3, Folder 24-35)
    (Includes letters of Harold Friedman, George Biddle, George Picken, Marion Bauer, Audrey McMahon, Michael Loew, Henry Lead, E. Nye, Frances M. Pollak, Stuart Davis, Harry Gottlieb, Ruth St. Denis, Ed B. Rowan, Michael Kiss, William C. Palmer, George Horowitz, Maurice Heaton, Paul Bird, Ethel Katz, Fred Knight, J. Scott Williams, Rockwell King, Alfred Barr, Elmer Rice, Nan Golden, Ellen Woodward, Joy Pride, Elizabeth Litchfield, Josephine Droege, Bianca Todd, A. Conger Goodyear, Philip Stein, Algot Stenbery, Arthur Emptage, Letteris Calapari, Ralph Mayer, Ernest Marbury, Corrington Gill, Daniel Cotton Rich, Joseph A. Danysh, Florence Kerr, Howard Lee Irwin, Adrian Dornbush, Hardinge Scholle, and F. Ballard Williams)
  - Artists' Council, U.S.A., circa 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    (Includes letters of Max Weber, José de Creeft, Thomas Hart Benton, and Carol Janeway)
  - Artists for Victory, Inc., 1941-1946; (6 folders; see also Box 8, sol) (Box 3, Folder 37-41)
    (Includes letters of Rockwell Kent, Chester Price, John Taylor Arms, Marie Kirkwood, Jim Eglern, Thomas C. Parker, and Erwin Barrie)
  - Committee to Defend V. J. Jerome, circa 1951-1956; (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 42-44)
    (Includes letters of Joseph North, Philip Evergood, Sara Gottlieb, and Rockwell Kent)
  - Committee to Defend V. J. Jerome, Bank Records, 1951-1954 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Committee to Defend V. J. Jerome, Published Writings by Jerome, 1947, 1951-1953 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    (Includes article "Let Us Grasp the Weapon of Culture," and booklet "Culture in a Changing World, a Marxist Approach")
  - Communist Party, circa 1931-1977 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Hungarian Word, Inc., 1953-1962, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 48-49)
  - Independent Voters Committee of the Arts, Sciences, and Professions (ASP), circa 1944-1954; (see also Box 8, sol) (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - John Reed Clubs, circa 1929-1934 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    ("Proposals for Activities of John Reed Clubs")
  - National Society of Mural Painters (Mural Artists Guild), circa 1936-1941; (4 folders) (Box 3, Folder 52-55)
  - New York City Art Commission, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    (Carbon copies of meeting minutes)
  - New York City Council for Art Week, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - United American Artists (formerly the Artists' Union), circa 1930-1940 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Other Organizations' Records, circa 1934-1962 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Oversized Organizational Records (See Box 3, f41 and f50) (Box 8 (sol))
  - Oversized Organizational Records (See Box 3, f31) (Box 9 (OV))
- Printed Materials, circa 1920-1986; Series 5; (Boxes 4-6, 8, and OV 9; 3 linear feet)
  This series contains newspaper clippings, exhibition catalogs, magazines, maps, pamphlets, greeting cards, brochures, mailings, flyers, posters, and books. Printed materials with artwork or writings by Hugo Gellert are filed under his name, as are documents promoting his public appearances and other activities. The remainder of the series is filed by type of material. Although the bulk of the printed materials series has been scanned, some clippings, announcements, invitations, maps, pamphlets, printed short stories, and publicity and mailings were not. Not scanned or partially scanned material is noted at the folder title.
  Gellert's illustrations are found in a wide variety of publications such as books, magazines, pamphlets, flyers, and publicity for various organizations. These materials are arranged by title, type of document, or organization. Serial publications that Gellert helped to produce are filed under the heading "Gellert periodicals." Photocopied clippings contain additional published Gellert illustrations and cartoons.
  Exhibition catalogs, announcements, and invitations are primarily for exhibitions in which Gellert was not a participant. Pamphlets are mostly political tracts. Multiple pamphlets are filed by publisher, and single instances are filed chronologically under a miscellaneous heading. Multiple periodicals are filed by title, with single instances filed chronologically as well.
  Publicity and mailings received by Gellert are arranged chronologically and include mass mailings such as form letters, flyers, newsletters, bulletins, announcements, circulars, press releases, reports, and other printed materials related to various labor, political, and art organizations. Some of the issues addressed in this material include the Spanish Civil War, advocacy for victims of McCarthyism, May Day demonstrations, civil rights, Soviet-American friendship, Cuba, organized labor, and education. Also found here are scattered programs for cultural events.
  Printed materials related to organizations in which Gellert was a principal organizer are found in the Organizational Records series. Exhibition catalogs for the Art of Today Gallery are also found with Organizational Records.
  - Clippings, circa 1934-1955 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Clippings (Photocopies of originals dated 1923-1982), circa 1986 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Announcements, and Invitations, circa 1932-1985; (8 folders; partially scanned; see also Box 8, sol) (Box 4, Folder 3-9)
  - Gellert Appearances and Publicity, circa 1930-1955 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Gellert Article on Art Young in ALA News, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Gellert Illustrations (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous Gellert Illustrations (Box 4)
      - Illustrations, circa 1927-1959; (partially scanned) (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Halftone Printing Block, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Proofs, circa 1920-1959 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Aesop Said So and Comrade Gulliver, circa 1935-1936; (See also Box 8, sol) (Box 4, Folder 15)
      (Proofs of illustrations for books by Gellert)
    - Elore, 1921; (See box 8, sol; partially scanned) (Box 4, Folder 16)
      (Hungarian-language Newspaper)
    - Fasizmus, undated; (partially scanned) (Box 4, Folder 17)
      (Anti-Horthy League Pamphlet)
    - The Fraternal Outlook, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      (magazine cover)
    - Greeting Cards, circa 1937-1960 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - "Lionel Atwill in The Outsider", circa 1929 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      (theater handbill)
    - Jefferson School of Social Science Catalogs, 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Magyarok Amerikában, 1951; (partially scanned) (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - May Day Committee, 1951-1959; (partially scanned) (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Mindentudó Kalendárium, 1955; (partially scanned) (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - New World Review, 1951; (partially scanned) (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - New York World, circa 1926-1927; (See also OV 9) (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Pearson's, 1922-1923 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      (magazine covers)
    - The President's Speech Illustrated by 19 Artists, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Tavasz a Dunán, 1956; (partially scanned) (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - The Worker, 36 Years, Drawings, 1960; (partially scanned) (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Gellert Periodicals (Box 4)
    - American Dialog, 1964-1972; (partially scanned) (Box 4, Folder 31-32)
    - Art Front, 1934-1936; (See Box 8, sol; scanned in entirety except duplicates) (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Magyar Szó (Hungarian Word), 1953-1959, 1963; (See Box 8, sol; partially scanned) (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - New Masses, 1926, 1933-1945; (See also Box 8, sol; partially scanned) (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Greeting Card Series, circa 1933 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Hungarian Short Stories, 1953, undated; (not scanned) (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - List of Artist Contributors to The Masses, Liberator, or New Masses, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Maps, circa 1950; (not scanned) (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Pamphlets, (Covers only scanned) (Box 4)
    - Pamphlets General File, 1935-1979; (4 folders) (Box 4, Folder 40-43)
    - American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born, circa 1953-1959 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Artists' Equity Association, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Communist Party, circa 1948-1950 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Foreign Languages Publishing House (Moscow), 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Hungarian Bulletin, 1949-1954 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, circa 1943-1962 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - New Century Publishers, 1945-1961; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
    - United Committee of South Slavic Americans, circa 1943-1946 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Workers' Library Publishers, 1935-1943 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Union-related Pamphlets, 1937-1985 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - United States Government, 1935-1941, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 12-13)
  - Periodicals, (Covers only scanned) (Box 5)
    - Periodicals General File, 1918-1962; (7 folders) (Box 5, Folder 14-20)
    - American Contemporary Art, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Amnesty Trumpet, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Bulletin of the World Council of Peace, 1956-1963 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - The Lamp, 1952-1959 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Latin American Facts, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - The Masses, 1916; (See Box 8, sol) (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Masses and Mainstream, 1950-1954; (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 27-29)
    - Mainstream, 1958, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - New Hungary, 1953-1955 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Publicity and Mailings, circa 1930-1940; (5 folders; not scanned) (Box 5, Folder 32-36)
  - Publicity and Mailings, 1941-1986, undated; (26 folders; not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 1-26)
  - Song books and Song sheets, circa 1932-1958 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Oversized Printed Materials (See Box 4, f9, f15-16, f33-35, and Box 5, f26) (Box 8 (sol))
  - Oversized Printed Materials (See Box 4, f26) (Box 9 (OV))
- Photographs, circa 1920-1959; Series 6; (Boxes 6-7; 0.5 linear feet)
  This series consists of personal photographs, news and publicity photographs, and photographs of works of art. Most of the personal photographs are snapshots, and most are unidentified. There are also two sets of group portraits with Gellert pictured, but other individuals are unidentified.
  The bulk of the photographs are publicity and news photographs, including photos from news agencies and file photos of public figures. Public figures include well-known American communists such as Earl Browder, Tom Mooney, Eugene Debs, Upton Sinclair, and Paul Robeson, as well as famous industrialists and mainstream politicians such as J.P. Morgan, Dwight Eisenhower, Herbert Hoover, and Robert Moses. Some of the photographs appear reproduced in the various publications Gellert helped to produce. Several news photographs are marked "D.W." or "Daily Worker." A few of those pictured were also subjects of Gellert's murals and illustrations. Others remain unidentified. Subjects with multiple photographs are listed in the folder headings, and single instances are filed in miscellaneous files.
  Photographs of works of art include murals by Gellert at Seward Park, a mural by Pablo O'Higgins in Mexico, and Philip Guston's mural for the 1939 World's Fair. Set pieces with illustrations by Gellert are shown during a performance, which may have taken place at the 1945 San Francisco conference of the United Nations.
  - Personal Photographs (Box 6)
    - Group Portraits with Gellert Pictured, circa 1930, circa 1950 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Family, circa 1938 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Friends, circa 1930-1959 (Box 6, Folder 30)
      (Included are photographs of Carl Schwartz, Julia Schwartz, Irving Fierson, Nancy Fierson, Dolores Gold, Max Bachner, Jenny Bachner, and other unidentified people)
    - Unidentified Buildings, circa 1957-1958 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Publicity and News Photographs (Box 6)
    - Earl Browder, circa 1930-1940 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Ben Davis, 1943-1948 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - John Gates, circa 1940-1950 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Tom Mooney, circa 1934-1942 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Paul Robeson, circa 1928-1950 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Upton Sinclair, circa 1930-1939 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Harry Winston, circa 1940-1950 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Miscellaneous Public Figures, circa 1920-1959; (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 39-41)
      (Pictured are Bernhard Stern, Walter Lowenfels, George Morris, Robert Moses, Al Smith, Eugene Debs, Julius Rosenberg, William Z. Foster, Irving Kaufman, Karl Marx, Maxim Gorky, B.W. Atwood, Jan Bratiano, Herbert Hoover, Walter S. Gifford, Eleanor Roosevelt, Edward R. Murrow, Dwight Eisenhower, Fred Seaton, Maud Barger-Wallach, Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney, Otto Kahn, J.P. Morgan, Pierre duPont, George Baker, Jr., J.D. Rockefeller, Jr., and Eugene Meyer)
    - Miscellaneous Public Figures, Unidentified, circa 1920-1959; (2 folders including negatives; negatives not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 42-43)
    - Unidentified People, undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Australian Livestock, circa 1950-1959; (not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Eastern European Culture, circa 1950-1959; (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 46-49)
    - Seward Park Slum Clearance Project, circa 1957 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Theater Production of E. Chodorov's Decision, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of Works of Art (Box 7)
    - Gellert's Seward Park Murals, circa 1961 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Theater Performance with Gellert Set Pieces, circa 1945 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Works of Art by Others (Box 7)
      - Murals, 1933, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Sculpture and Paintings, circa 1920-1959; (not scanned) (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Artwork, 1927-1981; Series 7; (Box 7, OV 10; 0.4 linear feet)
  Artwork includes silkscreen prints, lithographs, woodcuts, sketches, drawings, doodles, designs, sketchbooks, layouts for printed materials, and other print production elements. Artwork is by Hugo Gellert and others, including Philip Reisman, Gyula Derkovits, Anton Refregier.